Exercise 3-6, reading the uh sound. When you read the following schwa paragraph,
try clenching your teeth the first time. It won't sound completely natural, but it
will get rid of all the excess lip and jaw movement and force your tongue to work
harder than usual. Remember that in speaking American English we don't move
our lips much and we talk through our teeth from far back in our throats. I'm
going to read with my teeth clenched together and you follow along holding your
teeth together.
Some pundits proposed that the sun wonders unnecessarily about sundry and assorted
conundrums. One cannot but speculate what can come of their proposal. It wasn't
enough to trouble us, but it was done so underhandedly that hundreds of sun-lovers
rushed to the defense of their beloved sun. None of this was relevant on Monday,
however, when the sun burned up the entire country. Read What Must the Sun Above
Wonder About twice. Try it with your teeth clenched the first time and normally the
second time.